Guide to the Archives Union File (AUF), Section 6: Boxes 319.1-378
Archives Union File (AUF), Section 6: Boxes 319.1-378
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 363, Folder 5)
  - Item 5: Practical suggestions to A.F. of T. locals regarding modus operandi in democratizing school administration, 1953; Publication (Box 363, Folder 5)
  - Item 6: Community meetings a new approach to Trade Union Political Action, 1951; Publication (Box 363, Folder 5)
  - Item 7: A sample constitution for College Student Locals of the American Federation of Teachers, 1966; Publication (Box 363, Folder 5)
  - Item 8: An open letter to the National Executive Council of the American Federation of Teachers, 1941; Publication (Box 363, Folder 5)
  - Item 9: The Fact of the Chicago investigation, 1946; Publication (Box 363, Folder 5)
  - Item 10: Federation News, 1919; Publication (Box 363, Folder 5)
    Notes: vol. 2, no. 4 (1919)
  - Item 11: McCall's Magazine for September, 1910, 1919; Publication (Box 363, Folder 5)
- The Louisville Teacher, Publication (Box 363, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: The Louisville Teacher, 1949; Publication (Box 363, Folder 6)
    Notes: vol. 3, no. 6-8, 10 (1949)
  - Item 2: The Louisville Teacher, 1949; Publication (Box 363, Folder 6)
    Notes: vol. 4, no. 2 (1949)
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 363, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Address by President Carl J. Megel to the 47th Annual Convention of the AFT, 1963; Publication (Box 363, Folder 7)
    Author: Carl Megel
  - Item 2: Re: disability income and how it works, Publication (Box 363, Folder 7)
  - Item 3: Significance of the NYC Teachers Collective Bargaining Election, 1962; Publication (Box 363, Folder 7)
  - Item 4: Merit Rating Education Cancer., 1962; Publication (Box 363, Folder 7)
  - Item 5: article - A bill of rights for Teachers, Publication (Box 363, Folder 7)
  - Item 6: Freedom of choice, Publication (Box 363, Folder 7)
  - Item 7: Gains of the American Federation of Teachers, Publication (Box 363, Folder 7)
  - Item 8: Goals of the AFT and why, Publication (Box 363, Folder 7)
  - Item 9: Merit rating educationally unsound, Publication (Box 363, Folder 7)
  - Item 10: A teachers union leader views school problems, Publication (Box 363, Folder 7)
- Michigan Federation of Teachers, Publication (Box 363, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: The Minneapolis Teacher, 1946; Publication (Box 363, Folder 8)
    Notes: vol. 4, no.5
  - Item 2: The Minneapolis Teacher, 1949; Publication (Box 363, Folder 8)
    Notes: vol. 7, no. 5
  - Item 3: The Minneapolis Teacher, 1952; Publication (Box 363, Folder 8)
    Notes: vol. 10, no. 1
  - Item 4: The Michigan Teacher, 1942; Publication (Box 363, Folder 8)
    Notes: vol. 2, no. 1
  - Item 5: The Michigan Teacher, 1951; Publication (Box 363, Folder 8)
    Notes: vol. 10, no. 1- 3
  - Item 6: The Michigan Teacher, 1952; Publication (Box 363, Folder 8)
    Notes: vol. 11, no. 1- 2
  - Item 7: To Officers and Members of Labor Organizations - Re: abrupt suspension of the Workers Educational Service of the Univ. of Michigan, 1949; Publication (Box 363, Folder 8)
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 364, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Can teachers' unions be called out on strike?, 1920; Publication (Box 364, Folder 1)
  - Item 2: Design for an effective schools program in urban centers, 1966; Publication (Box 364, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: Report: showing results of fifteen years of organization to the teachers of Chicago, 1908; Publication (Box 364, Folder 1)
    Author: Chicago Teachers' Federation
  - Item 4: article reprinted from the Educational Review - vol. 60, no. 2, 1920; Publication (Box 364, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: Professional organization of Teachers, 1919; Publication (Box 364, Folder 1)
    Author: John Dewey
  - Item 6: A call to action, 1916; Publication (Box 364, Folder 1)
    Author: Charles B. Stillman
  - Item 7: Code of ethics, 1920; Publication (Box 364, Folder 1)
  - Item 8: Shake your head and be dismissed!, 1917; Publication (Box 364, Folder 1)
  - Item 9: Program of action, 1931; Publication (Box 364, Folder 1)
  - Item 10: A new look at MES, Publication (Box 364, Folder 1)
  - Item 11: The more effective schools program in NYC, Publication (Box 364, Folder 1)
  - Item 12: Effective schools for all children, Publication (Box 364, Folder 1)
  - Item 13: More effective schools programAFT's answer to the Ghetto School problem, Publication (Box 364, Folder 1)
  - Item 14: Labor and education at the Atlantic City Convention, 1916; Publication (Box 364, Folder 1)
  - Item 15: Objections to the union movement among teachers answered, 1916; Publication (Box 364, Folder 1)
    Author: L. V. Lampson
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 364, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: A critical evaluation of the American Federation of Teachers, 1934; Publication (Box 364, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: A critical evaluation of the American Federation of Teachers, 1934; Publication (Box 364, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: The Teacher and the Public, Publication (Box 364, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: American Federation of Teachers Bulletin - Jan. 15, 1935, Publication (Box 364, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: American Teacher - Convention Number - Oct. 1932 - vol. XVII, no. 1, Publication (Box 364, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: The progressive group program for the Teachers Union, 1935; Publication (Box 364, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: A program of objectives of the American Federation of Teachers (adopted by the Seventeenth Convention, American Federation of Teachers, 1933; Publication (Box 364, Folder 2)
  - Item 8: Manual of common procedure for the use of local unions, 1934; Publication (Box 364, Folder 2)
  - Item 9: Oaths of loyalty for teachers, 1935; Publication (Box 364, Folder 2)
    Author: Henry R. Linville
  - Item 10: The college teacher and the trade union, 1936; Publication (Box 364, Folder 2)
    Author: College Section of the Teachers Union, Local 5
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 364, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Program - Twenty-fifth annual convention, 1941; Publication (Box 364, Folder 3)
  - Item 2: Accomplishments of the American Federation of Teachers, 1937; Publication (Box 364, Folder 3)
  - Item 3: Labor's stand on school finance, 1941; Publication (Box 364, Folder 3)
  - Item 4: Declarations of the American Federation of Labor on education, 1941; Publication (Box 364, Folder 3)
  - Item 5: The Jerome Davis case; final report of an investigation, 1937; Publication (Box 364, Folder 3)
    Notes: Conducted by the American Federation of Teachers into the proposed dismissal of Professor Jerome Davis from the Stark Chair of practical philanthropy at the Yale Divinity School. 2 copies
  - Item 6: The Keeney case: big business, higher education, and organized labor, report of an investigation, 1939; Publication (Box 364, Folder 3)
    Author: National Academic Freedom Committee
    Notes: Made by the National Academic Freedom Committee of the American Federation of Teachers into the causes of the recent dismissal of Professor Philip O. Keeney, librarian, from Montana state university and the role played by certain business and political in
  - Item 7: Tales of ten cities - stories of programs of action and of actual accomplishments of typical locals of the American Federation of Teachers, 1938; Publication (Box 364, Folder 3)
  - Item 8: Statement of the Independent Group 1939, Publication (Box 364, Folder 3)
  - Item 9: 24th National Convention, 1940; Publication (Box 364, Folder 3)
  - Item 10: aritcle-Teachers clear decks for action, 1940; Publication (Box 364, Folder 3)
    Author: Mark Starr
  - Item 11: Millions of Workers through their official representatives, 1936; Publication (Box 364, Folder 3)
  - Item 12: The National union of teachers of England, 1938; Publication (Box 364, Folder 3)
    Author: Elsie Parker
  - Item 13: Academic Freedom, 1938; Publication (Box 364, Folder 3)
  - Item 14: Address of President Jerome Davis - Twenty-second annual convention, 1938; Publication (Box 364, Folder 3)
    Author: Jerome Davis
  - Item 15: Frontiers in academic freedom 1937-1938 - address by Arnold Shukotoff, Publication (Box 364, Folder 3)
    Author: Arnold Shukotoff
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: British teachers and the war, 1942; Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
    Author: National Union of Teachers
    Notes: A resume of three years of dramatic educational service under unprecedented conditions of total war, as revealed in the proceedings of the first annual convention of the National union of teachers since 1939. Selected and reprinted from official publicati
  - Item 2: Do white collar workers need unions?, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
    Notes: Analysis of the economic status of white collar workers in wartime
  - Item 3: Facts: answers to questions commonly asked about the American Federation of Teachers., 1943; Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 4: Questions and answers about the American Federation of Teachers, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 5: Information about the American Federation of Teachers, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 6: What 17 cents will do in AFT dues, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 7: Can Teachers' unions be called out on strike?, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 8: Labor and the schools in the present crisis, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 9: Labor's stand on school finance, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 10: A dad's letter to a marine Raider on strikes, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 11: If you are in doubt, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 12: Should teachers be neutral, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 13: What the church thinks of labor, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 14: Labor's battle for education, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 15: Handi-kit, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 16: An appreciation of an important editorial on the Civil Rights of Teachers, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 17: Don't let the schools suffer, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 18: The keys to progress our public schools, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 19: The answer to the chaos in Teachers' organizations, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 20: Labor education and the war, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 21: Labor's program of education for the classroom teachers of America, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 22: The Teachers' union gets down to work, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 23: Teachers clear decks for action, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 24: New York Teacher, 1941; Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
    Notes: (May 1941)
  - Item 25: Membership of all locals in good standing as of August 9, 1941, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 26: Report of Vice President E. Max Wales, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
    Author: E. Max Wales
  - Item 27: Continue effective union campaigns - vote the administration slate, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 28: Committee to save the American Federation of Teachers in order to protect the schools: a plea for unity in the AFT, 1941; Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 29: Labor as Equal Partner, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 30: The New American - April 1, 1940, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 31: Labor, education and democracy, 1941; Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
    Notes: Excerpts from an address before the annual convention of the Wisconsin state federation of labor. August 18, 1941.
  - Item 32: Teacher organization and democracy in school administration, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
    Author: George E. Axtelle
  - Item 33: The right of public employees to organize, bargain collectively: a statement by the Atotorney-General of Nebraska, 1943; Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Item 34: The Union in 1939, Publication (Box 364, Folder 4)
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Tentative outline of convention program, 1947; Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 2: Roster, 1949; Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: Program - thirtieth annual convention, 1947; Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 4: News Letter, 1948; Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 5: Organized teachers fight for democracy, 1946; Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
    Notes: Article reprinted from the American Federationist - Official Journal of the American Federation of Labor, May, 1946. 2 copies
  - Item 6: Angry Americans, 1946; Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
    Notes: Article reprinted from the American Federationist, for Dec. 1946. 2 copies
  - Item 7: Academic freedom in a time of crisis, 1948; Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
    Author: Celia Lewis; Vera Shlakman; Louis Jaffe
    Notes: Prepared by Celia Lewis, Vera Shlakman, Louis Jaffe, with the assistance of the Academic Freedom Committee of the New York Teachers Union.
  - Item 8: Basic principles of federal aid to education, 1946; Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
    Author: Floyd W. Reeves
    Notes: Exceprts from the testimony of Dr. Floyd Reeves before the Senate Committee on labor and education. 2 copies
  - Item 9: Do white collar workers need unions?, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
    Notes: Analysis of the economic status of white collar workers in wartime. 2nd copy
  - Item 10: Teachers' unions in England, France and the United States, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 11: Should college teachers affiliate with labor?, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 12: Federal aid and the crisis in American education, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 13: A challenge to class-room teachers, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 14: What labor has done for American children, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 15: Organized labor and the public schools, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 16: Labor's answer to the teacher shortage problem, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 17: Company unions and the school crisis, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 18: What 24 cents per month will do in AFT dues, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 19: Why I joined, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 20: Democracy in education, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 21: Should teachers' salaries be based on rating, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 22: Education in the atomic age, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 23: A golden opportunity, 1939; Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 24: A program of action for classroom teachers, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 25: Teachers should organize, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 26: Tales of ten cities - stories of programs of action and of actual accomplishments of typical locals of the American Federation of Teachers, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 27: Labor, business and farmers urge increased salaries for teachers, 1947; Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
    Notes: Reprinted from the AF of L weekly news service. 2 copies
  - Item 28: 4-point plan adopted by AFT group to meet present teachers' problems, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
    Notes: Reprinted from the AF of L weekly news service
  - Item 29: AFL teachers register major gains in chartering of 72 local chapters, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 30: AF of T Roster growth of membership 1916-1917 to 1946-47, 1916-1947 (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 31: Publicity Bulletin - Chicago, Ill. - Three teacher union members were elected to the Congress of the United States, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 32: Company unions and the school crisis, 1947; Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
    Notes: Article reprinted from the Feb. 1947 issue of the American Federationist. 2 copies
  - Item 33: City, State officials accused of forcing accused of forcing strikes of teachers, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 34: Organized labor and the public schools, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 35: Green asks all unions to back teachers' plea for higher pay, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 36: How we deny our children, 1947; Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
    Author: A. N. Spanel
  - Item 37: Special Radio Announcement - AF of T Vice President to Broadcast on Federal Aid over Nationwide hook-up of CBS, 1947; Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 38: Company unions and the school crisis, 1947; Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 39: Labor's answer to the teacher shortage problem, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 40: Should professionally-minded teachers affiliate with labor?, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 41: Selected statements, 1949; Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 42: Teachers--the union way, Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
    Author: John M. Eklund
  - Item 43: Teachers Bulletin, 1950; Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
    Notes: vol. 1, no. 5
  - Item 44: The American Federation of Teachers, 1946; Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Item 45: To provide for the common defense, 1948; Publication (Box 364, Folder 5)
    Author: John L. Childs; George S. Counts, Floyd W. Reeves
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Unfair practices in teacher rating, Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: Flying around the world on a labor-education tour: selected letters, 1953; Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
  - Item 3: Your pension: the AFT fights to protect it by Irvin Kuenzli and Social security for teachers, Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
    Author: Selma Borchardt; Irvin Kuenzli
  - Item 4: Classroom teachers causcus, Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
  - Item 5: What 33 cents per moth will do in AFT dues, Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
  - Item 6: Labor and education in the present crisis, Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
  - Item 7: meet the teachers union, Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
  - Item 8: Do white collar workers need unions?, Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
  - Item 9: What membership in the American Federation of Teachers means..., Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
  - Item 10: What is the teacher worth?, Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
  - Item 11: Questions and answers about the American Federation of Teachers, Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
  - Item 12: The Defense Machinery of the AF of T, Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
  - Item 13: A charter of the rights of the child, Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
  - Item 14: North Carolina AFL fights Congress slur on teachers, 1951; Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
    Notes: Newspaper clipping. AFL Weekly News Service
  - Item 15: The union in action in 1952 (report to the 35th Annual Convention), Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
  - Item 16: A message to those who are considering teaching as a career, 1953; Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
  - Item 17: Memorandum on grievance prodedure, Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
  - Item 18: Some judicial decisions affecting dismissal of teachers for political and religious reasons, Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
    Author: Myron Tripp
  - Item 19: Suggestions re publicity and press relations, Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
  - Item 20: Legal and legislative materials on collective bargaining rights for public employees, 1951; Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
    Author: John Ligtenberg
  - Item 21: Teacher organization and democracy in school administration, Publication (Box 364, Folder 6)
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: A survey of 1955-56 teacher salary schedules in 933 U.S. cities, 1956; Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
    Author: Florence Roehm Greve
    Notes: Compiled from figures furnished by the respective superintendents of schools in these cities.
  - Item 2: Conformists, informers or free teachers, 1953; Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
    Notes: Excerpts from the trials of seven New York City teachers dismissed on Thursday, January 8, 1953.
  - Item 3: Discipline: what for and how?, 1957; Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
    Author: Mary Herrick
  - Item 4: Constitution - as adopted at the Seventeenth Convention, 1916; Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: Financial comparisons of public schools by states, 1959; Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: A Teachers union leader views school problems, 1958; Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: Questions and answers about the American Federation of Teachers, Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Item 8: How the school dollar is spent in our largest cities, Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Item 9: Yes you can, 1959; Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Item 10: Teaching as a career, Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Item 11: Amendments submitted by locals before the 1955 Convention and considered by Constitutional Amendments Committee, Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Item 12: Proposed changes in National Constitution, 1955; Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Item 13: New horizons for America's teachers, Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Item 14: Newark School Board Statements, Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Item 15: Working for Teachers of today and tomorrow, Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Item 16: Why I joined the AFT, Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Item 17: Meet Workers' Education Local 189, Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Item 18: Procedures in collective bargaining, Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
    Author: George Harrison
  - Item 19: Inside your public schools.., Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Item 20: Why I joined the AF of T, Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Item 21: Goals of the AFL-CIO American Federation of Teachers and WHY, Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Item 22: Report of the American Teacher, 1954-1955 (Box 365, Folder 1)
    Author: Marie L. Caylor
  - Item 23: Personnel relations for teachers, 1959; Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
    Author: George S. Reuter
  - Item 24: Primer for new teachers, 1954; Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
    Author: Teachers' Union of the City of New York
  - Item 25: Publicity handbook, 1956; Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Item 26: Union philosophy and the professional, 1957; Publication (Box 365, Folder 1)
    Author: Jack Barbash
- AFT (American Federation of Teachers), Publication (Box 365, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: A report by Carl J. Megel, president, to the convention of the American Federation of Teachers - Fort Wayne, Indiana, 1955; Publication (Box 365, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: Flying around the world on a labor-education tour, 1953; Publication (Box 365, Folder 2)
    Notes: Selected letters by Irvin R. Kuenzli.
  - Item 3: Resolution No. 17 (submitted by the Denver Federation of Teachers), 1955; Publication (Box 365, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: As revised by resolutions committee (Resolution No. 22), 1955; Publication (Box 365, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: Resolution No. 21 - The following delegates to the 38th Annual Convention., 1955; Publication (Box 365, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: Resolution No. 2 - Submitted by the Executive Committee of the Empire State Federation of TeachersExpansion of political activity, 1955; Publication (Box 365, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: Progressive caucusThe Progressive Caucus is an informally organized group of delegages which gets together to secure information, clarify opinion, and plan action on convention issues., 1955; Publication (Box 365, Folder 2)
  - Item 8: Resolution No. 18 - Support for emergency and long-range Federal aid program, 1955; Publication (Box 365, Folder 2)
  - Item 9: Radio and Television Programs - 38th Annual Convention - American Federation of Teachers, 1955; Publication (Box 365, Folder 2)
  - Item 10: Report of the International Relations Committee, 1955; Publication (Box 365, Folder 2)